<?xml version="1.0"?>
<info>
	<id>ncc_backend_4mc</id>
	<name>NC Connector for mail integration</name>
	<summary lang="en">Central policies, templates, signatures and password delivery for NC Connector mail add-ons.</summary>
	<summary lang="de">Zentrale Richtlinien, Vorlagen, Signaturen und Passwortzustellung für NC Connector Mail-Add-ons.</summary>
	<description lang="en"><![CDATA[
# NC Connector for mail integration

NC Connector Backend is the central policy and template app for NC Connector mail add-ons.

The Thunderbird and Outlook Classic add-ons can run without this backend. This app adds central policy control, Seat assignment, managed email signatures, custom templates and password delivery rules for organizations.

## What the backend adds

- Central Share, Talk and email-signature policies for Thunderbird and Outlook Classic
- Seat assignment for Nextcloud users
- Group and user overrides for teams with different rules
- Managed HTML templates for Share blocks, password mails, Talk invitations and email signatures
- Separate password delivery as plaintext mail or Nextcloud Secret Link
- Optional Secrets app integration for expiring password links
- Setup diagnostics for mail clients when backend access is not available

## Share policies

Admins can define default share folders, share names, permissions, password behavior and expiry days.

Large attachments can be routed into Nextcloud based on central rules. The mail clients insert clean Share blocks with link, password information, rights and expiry date.

## Password delivery

Separate password delivery can use two modes:

- Plaintext: send the password in a separate follow-up mail
- Nextcloud Secret Link: send an expiring Secrets link instead of the raw password

If the Nextcloud Secrets app is missing or disabled, clients fall back to the existing plaintext password mail behavior.

## Email signatures

The backend can provide one central HTML signature template for Thunderbird and Outlook Classic.

Signature values can come from Nextcloud user profiles and per-user override fields. Empty placeholders remove their surrounding line or table row before the signature is sent to the mail client.

## Talk meetings

Admins can define Talk defaults for calendar-based meeting creation, including room type, lobby, visibility, password behavior and invitation templates.

## When this backend is useful

Use this backend when an organization needs central defaults, locked settings, Seat assignment, managed templates, managed signatures or password delivery rules.

Single users can still use the mail add-ons without this backend.

## Mail clients

- Thunderbird: [https://addons.thunderbird.net/thunderbird/addon/nc4tb/](https://addons.thunderbird.net/thunderbird/addon/nc4tb/)
- Outlook Classic: [https://github.com/nc-connector/NC_Connector_for_Outlook/releases/latest](https://github.com/nc-connector/NC_Connector_for_Outlook/releases/latest)

## More information

- Homepage: [https://nc-connector.de](https://nc-connector.de)
- Contact: [https://nc-connector.de/kontakt/](https://nc-connector.de/kontakt/)
]]></description>
	<description lang="de"><![CDATA[
# NC Connector für Mail-Integration

NC Connector Backend ist die zentrale Richtlinien- und Vorlagen-App für die NC Connector Mail-Add-ons.

Die Thunderbird- und Outlook-Classic-Add-ons können auch ohne dieses Backend genutzt werden. Diese App ergänzt zentrale Richtlinien, Seat-Zuweisung, verwaltete E-Mail-Signaturen, eigene Vorlagen und Passwortzustellregeln für Organisationen.

## Was das Backend ergänzt

- Zentrale Freigabe-, Talk- und E-Mail-Signatur-Richtlinien für Thunderbird und Outlook Classic
- Seat-Zuweisung für Nextcloud-Benutzer
- Gruppen- und Benutzerüberschreibungen für Teams mit unterschiedlichen Regeln
- Verwaltete HTML-Vorlagen für Freigabeblöcke, Passwort-Mails, Talk-Einladungen und E-Mail-Signaturen
- Separate Passwortzustellung als Klartext-Mail oder Nextcloud Secret-Link
- Optionale Secrets-App-Integration für ablaufende Passwort-Links
- Setup-Diagnosen für Mail-Clients, wenn der Backend-Zugriff nicht verfügbar ist

## Freigabe-Richtlinien

Admins können Standardordner, Freigabenamen, Berechtigungen, Passwortverhalten und Ablaufdauer zentral festlegen.

Große Anhänge können nach zentralen Regeln in Nextcloud ausgelagert werden. Die Mail-Clients fügen saubere Freigabeblöcke mit Link, Passwortinformation, Rechten und Ablaufdatum ein.

## Passwortzustellung

Separate Passwortzustellung kann zwei Modi nutzen:

- Klartext: Passwort in einer separaten Folge-Mail senden
- Nextcloud Secret-Link: ablaufenden Secrets-Link statt Rohpasswort senden

Wenn die Nextcloud Secrets App fehlt oder deaktiviert ist, nutzen die Clients weiter die bestehende Klartext-Passwort-Mail.

## E-Mail-Signaturen

Das Backend kann eine zentrale HTML-Signaturvorlage für Thunderbird und Outlook Classic bereitstellen.

Signaturwerte können aus Nextcloud-Benutzerprofilen und benutzerbezogenen Zusatzfeldern kommen. Leere Platzhalter entfernen ihre umgebende Zeile oder Tabellenzeile, bevor die Signatur an den Mail-Client gesendet wird.

## Talk-Meetings

Admins können Talk-Defaults für kalenderbasierte Besprechungen festlegen, inklusive Raumtyp, Lobby, Sichtbarkeit, Passwortverhalten und Einladungsvorlagen.

## Wann dieses Backend sinnvoll ist

Dieses Backend ist sinnvoll, wenn eine Organisation zentrale Defaults, gesperrte Einstellungen, Seat-Zuweisung, verwaltete Vorlagen, verwaltete Signaturen oder Passwortzustellregeln braucht.

Einzelne Nutzer können die Mail-Add-ons weiterhin ohne dieses Backend verwenden.

## Mail-Clients

- Thunderbird: [https://addons.thunderbird.net/thunderbird/addon/nc4tb/](https://addons.thunderbird.net/thunderbird/addon/nc4tb/)
- Outlook Classic: [https://github.com/nc-connector/NC_Connector_for_Outlook/releases/latest](https://github.com/nc-connector/NC_Connector_for_Outlook/releases/latest)

## Weitere Informationen

- Homepage: [https://nc-connector.de](https://nc-connector.de)
- Kontakt: [https://nc-connector.de/kontakt/](https://nc-connector.de/kontakt/)
]]></description>
	<version>1.1.1</version>
	<licence>AGPL-3.0-or-later</licence>
	<author mail="info@nc-connector.de" homepage="https://nc-connector.de">NC Connector</author>
	<namespace>NcConnector</namespace>
	<category>integration</category>
	<category>tools</category>
	<website>https://nc-connector.de</website>
	<bugs>https://nc-connector.de/kontakt/</bugs>
	<screenshot>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/nc-connector/.github/refs/heads/main/profile/header-solid-blue.png</screenshot>
	<screenshot>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/nc-connector/Server_Backend/main/screenshots/appsettings.png</screenshot>
	<screenshot>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/nc-connector/Server_Backend/main/screenshots/TemplateEditor.png</screenshot>
	<screenshot>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/nc-connector/Server_Backend/main/screenshots/email_sig.png</screenshot>
	<screenshot>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/nc-connector/NC_Connector_for_Thunderbird/main/screenshots/talk_wizzard1.png</screenshot>
	<screenshot>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/nc-connector/NC_Connector_for_Thunderbird/main/screenshots/filelink_wizzard1.png</screenshot>

	<dependencies>
		<nextcloud min-version="31" max-version="34"/>
		<php min-version="8.1"/>
	</dependencies>

	<background-jobs>
		<job>OCA\NcConnector\Cron\LicenseSyncJob</job>
		<job>OCA\NcConnector\Cron\UpdateCheckJob</job>
	</background-jobs>

	<commands>
		<command>OCA\NcConnector\Command\AdminSeatAssignmentCommand</command>
	</commands>

	<repair-steps>
		<pre-migration>
			<step>OCA\NcConnector\Setup\InstallSchema</step>
		</pre-migration>
		<install>
			<step>OCA\NcConnector\Setup\InstallSchema</step>
		</install>
		<uninstall>
			<step>OCA\NcConnector\Setup\UninstallCleanup</step>
		</uninstall>
	</repair-steps>

	<settings>
		<admin>OCA\NcConnector\Settings\Admin</admin>
		<admin-section>OCA\NcConnector\Settings\AdminSection</admin-section>
	</settings>
</info>
