<?xml version="1.0"?>
<info>
	<id>ncc_backend_4mc</id>
	<name>NC Connector for mail integration</name>
	<summary lang="en">Secure file sharing, Talk meetings and intelligent attachment handling directly in your familiar email client.</summary>
	<summary lang="de">Sicheres Teilen, Talk-Meetings und intelligente Anhangsverarbeitung direkt im gewohnten Mail-Client.</summary>
	<description lang="en"><![CDATA[
# NC Connector for mail integration

NC Connector brings secure sharing, Talk meetings, and intelligent attachment handling directly into Thunderbird and Outlook Classic. This keeps daily work inside the familiar mail and calendar workflow instead of constantly moving back to the browser.

## What NC Connector simplifies

- Share files securely directly from the email workflow
- Create and maintain Talk rooms directly from calendar events
- Move attachments above a defined size into Nextcloud when appropriate
- Insert links, passwords, and expiry dates in a clean and consistent way

## Feature set

### Share files securely

- Guided share dialog with expiry date, permissions, and note
- Password-protected shares
- Formatted share block with link, password, rights, and expiry date
- Optional separate password delivery

### Handle attachments intelligently

- Optionally route files through NC Connector by default
- Offer uploads above a configurable file-size threshold
- Clear user decision instead of uncontrolled automation
- ZIP-download and download-link workflows for external recipients

### Create Talk meetings from the calendar

- Create and update Talk rooms from events
- Manage room type, lobby, password, and moderation
- Keep title and meeting link synchronized with the event
- Clean up data for moved or deleted appointments

## Backend note

NC Connector also works directly in the mail client.  
With the optional Nextcloud backend, administrators additionally get central policies, Seat assignment, separate password delivery, and custom templates and branding for shares and Talk invitations.

That makes NC Connector suitable both for individual users and for organizations that want to manage mail and calendar workflows centrally.

## Mail clients

- Thunderbird: [https://addons.thunderbird.net/thunderbird/addon/nc4tb/](https://addons.thunderbird.net/thunderbird/addon/nc4tb/)
- Outlook Classic: [https://github.com/nc-connector/NC_Connector_for_Outlook/releases/latest](https://github.com/nc-connector/NC_Connector_for_Outlook/releases/latest)

## More information

- Homepage: [https://nc-connector.de](https://nc-connector.de)
- Contact: [https://nc-connector.de/kontakt/](https://nc-connector.de/kontakt/)
]]></description>
	<description lang="de"><![CDATA[
# NC Connector für Mail-Integration

NC Connector bringt sicheres Teilen, Talk-Meetings und intelligente Anhangsverarbeitung direkt in Thunderbird und Outlook Classic. So bleibt die Arbeit im gewohnten Mail- und Kalender-Workflow, ohne ständig in den Browser wechseln zu müssen.

## Was NC Connector erleichtert

- Dateien sicher direkt aus dem E-Mail-Workflow heraus teilen
- Talk-Räume direkt aus Kalendereinträgen erstellen und pflegen
- Anhänge ab einer definierten Größe gezielt in Nextcloud auslagern
- Links, Passwörter und Ablaufdaten sauber und einheitlich einfügen

## Funktionsumfang

### Dateien sicher teilen

- Geführter Freigabe-Dialog mit Ablaufdatum, Berechtigungen und Notiz
- Passwortgeschützte Freigaben
- Formatierter Freigabeblock mit Link, Passwort, Rechten und Ablaufdatum
- Optionaler separater Passwortversand

### Anhänge intelligent verarbeiten

- Dateien auf Wunsch immer über NC Connector teilen
- Upload-Angebot ab konfigurierbarer Dateigröße
- Klare Entscheidung statt unkontrollierter Automatik
- ZIP-Downloads und Download-Link-Workflows für externe Empfänger

### Talk direkt aus dem Kalender

- Talk-Räume aus Terminen erstellen und aktualisieren
- Raumtyp, Lobby, Passwort und Moderation verwalten
- Titel und Besprechungslink mit dem Termin synchron halten
- Aufräumen bei verschobenen oder gelöschten Terminen

## Hinweis zum Backend

NC Connector funktioniert auch direkt im Mail-Client.  
Mit dem optionalen Nextcloud-Backend kommen zusätzlich zentrale Richtlinien, Seat-Zuweisung, separate Passwortzustellung sowie eigene Vorlagen und Designs für Freigaben und Talk-Einladungen hinzu.

Damit eignet sich NC Connector sowohl für einzelne Nutzer als auch für Organisationen, die Mail- und Kalenderprozesse zentral steuern möchten.

## Mail-Clients

- Thunderbird: [https://addons.thunderbird.net/thunderbird/addon/nc4tb/](https://addons.thunderbird.net/thunderbird/addon/nc4tb/)
- Outlook Classic: [https://github.com/nc-connector/NC_Connector_for_Outlook/releases/latest](https://github.com/nc-connector/NC_Connector_for_Outlook/releases/latest)

## Weitere Informationen

- Homepage: [https://nc-connector.de](https://nc-connector.de)
- Kontakt: [https://nc-connector.de/kontakt/](https://nc-connector.de/kontakt/)
]]></description>
	<version>1.0.1</version>
	<licence>AGPL-3.0-or-later</licence>
	<author mail="info@nc-connector.de" homepage="https://nc-connector.de">NC Connector</author>
	<namespace>NcConnector</namespace>
	<category>integration</category>
	<category>tools</category>
	<website>https://nc-connector.de</website>
	<bugs>https://nc-connector.de/kontakt/</bugs>
	<screenshot>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/nc-connector/.github/refs/heads/main/profile/header-solid-blue.png</screenshot>
	<screenshot>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/nc-connector/Server_Backend/main/screenshots/appsettings.png</screenshot>
	<screenshot>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/nc-connector/Server_Backend/refs/heads/main/screenshots/TemplateEditor.png</screenshot>
	<screenshot>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/nc-connector/NC_Connector_for_Thunderbird/main/screenshots/talk_wizzard1.png</screenshot>
	<screenshot>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/nc-connector/NC_Connector_for_Thunderbird/main/screenshots/filelink_wizzard1.png</screenshot>

	<dependencies>
		<nextcloud min-version="31" max-version="34"/>
		<php min-version="8.1"/>
	</dependencies>

	<background-jobs>
		<job>OCA\NcConnector\Cron\LicenseSyncJob</job>
	</background-jobs>

	<repair-steps>
		<pre-migration>
			<step>OCA\NcConnector\Setup\InstallSchema</step>
		</pre-migration>
		<install>
			<step>OCA\NcConnector\Setup\InstallSchema</step>
		</install>
		<uninstall>
			<step>OCA\NcConnector\Setup\UninstallCleanup</step>
		</uninstall>
	</repair-steps>

	<settings>
		<admin>OCA\NcConnector\Settings\Admin</admin>
		<admin-section>OCA\NcConnector\Settings\AdminSection</admin-section>
	</settings>
</info>
